Now let us look at set associative
caches. We say that a cache is nway set
associative when a particular block can
be in one of n possible lines where it
can go. So the overall cache now is
divided into regions called sets. In
this case we have four sets. A given
block can go to one of its sets. So
pretty much we use some bits of the
block's address to tell us which set
does it need to go in within a set.
There could be a number of lines that
can contain a block. In this case, we
have a two-way set associative cache
because there are two lines in a set. So
a given block could be in either of the
two lines. Note that different blocks
might go to different sets. But a
particular block will map to one set and
then it has a choice between the two
lines there. In this particular cache,
we have eight lines, four sets, and two
ways. Note that n is two here. So we say
that the cache is two-way set
associative not when it has two sets but
when there is two blocks in each